

Ayşe Aker Tütüncü

Full-Stack Developer

- Amsterdam, Netherlands
- akerayse@gmail.com
- **S** links.dev/ayse
- in linkedin.com/in/ayseakr
- github.com/AyseAkr

SKILLS

HTTP/REST API Java JUnit **SQL** HTML **CSS JavaScript TypeScript** React Mocha git Docker Agile/SCRUM **TDD MS Office MS Visio** Android **Python**

LANGUAGES

Turkish

English

Native

Professional

Hi, I'm Ayse, a Full-Stack Developer based in Amsterdam. I graduated from software engineering and carried out my professional carrier as a business analyst and technical product manager. I worked with banks and fintech companies, improving my skills in understanding client needs, creating a scope of work in agreement with the client. After moving to Amsterdam, I decided to go back to my software engineering roots and pursue my carrier as a full stack Java developer. Now, I am eagerly anticipating the opportunity to utilize these skills on my journey as a developer. Outside of work, I enjoy traveling, cooking, and listening to music.

EDUCATION & TRAINING

School of Applied Technology </salt>

(May 2023 -Present) Bahçeşehir University

(Oct 2021 - Feb

2023)

Full-Stack Java Developer

Master's Degree, Executive

MBA

Completed the business administration for executives program to improve management skills

Kristianstad University

(Oct 2013 - Sep 2014) İstanbul Aydın University

(Sep 2011 - Jun 2016)

Exchange Program, Computer Science

learning

Studied for a year in Sweeden with Erasmus exchange program, learned Android development using Greenfoot

Intensive three month training program for

full stack web development with a focus on

TDD, mob programming, and applied

Bachelor's Degree, Software Engineering

Acquired theoretical and practical knowledge of computer science and software engineering, was vice president of IEEE student club, completed multiple projects and internships

WORK EXPERIENCE

1. DgPays - dgpays.com

(Sep 2021 - Apr 2023)

Technical Product Manager

- Gather client requirements, write scope documents, and collaborate with IT, analysis, and software teams
- Own and manage Direct Carrier Billing (DCB) and Insurance API Gateway products
- DCB responsibilities include integrating with mobile operators, transaction processing, reconciliation, fraud/risk analysis, and merchant onboarding
- Deeply involved in DCB analysis and testing processes
- Insurance product integration with Türkiye Sigorta and management of DASK, traffic and vehicle insurances, offer and policy creation and management, cancellations, request management, and integration with PTT.

2. Intertech - intertech.com.tr

(Nov 2020 - Sep 2021)

Senior Business Analyst

- Worked in the ATM team
- Involved in planning, analysis, and testing of ATM functions for multiple banks such as Denizbank, HSBC, OdeaBank, and PTT
- Contributed to the common ATM project to handle functional requirements
- Participated in method analysis and process planning for the first-ever private bank common ATM integration with Denizbank
- Analyzed a project to improve consensus processes and help operation teams detect issues in master accounts or ATM cassette counters
- Worked on a customer feedback project that enabled customers to give feedback directly at the ATM in case of hardware malfunction, with the aim of improving customer satisfaction
- Analyzed and tested Denizbank's credit card bill payments with QR.

TRAININGS

EMV

ВКМ

Test & Certification Processes

ВКМ

Gamified Agile/SCRUM

ACM

Client Needs & Software Requirements

Udacity

Java & Android

BilgeAdam

PERSONAL PROJECTS

International Karate Game

Term Project from Kristianstad University
I developed it using Greenfoot.

INR Tracking Application

Term Project from İstanbul Aydın University Junior Year

It is an application to monitor blood values of a patient. It allows navigating to the nearest hospital and calling for help in case of emergencies.

Smart Home & Office

Final Project from İstanbul Aydın University

It is a mobile application. It lets you control the lights and power, get notified when there is an outage or danger, locking/unlocking the doors. It utilizes NFC tags placed in your home and office.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

IEEE İstanbul Aydın University

Vice president of IEEE student club

Düşün Taşın Derneği

Non-profit organization

WORK EXPERIENCE

3. Turkish Economy Bank - teb.com.tr

Business Analyst

- Worked in the ATM team
- Contributed to the completion and deployment of all processes for the new ATM software
- Conducted device tests with Maestro at XFS layer
- Worked on testing ATM consensus processes and supply flows
- Performed NCR kernel certification tests for MasterCard and VISA
- Conducted general function tests, including cash withdrawal/deposit, credit card, and Notonus flows
- Analyzed journal data and ATM operation logs at back-office screens to deliver meaningful data to operation teams
- Worked on the analysis of refunds, including when and how they should be made and the acceleration of in-advance refunds to improve customer satisfaction.

4. OBSS - obss.tech

(Jan 2017 - Dec 2018)

(Dec 2018 - Nov 2020)

Business Analyst

- Consultant at Turkish Economy Bank (TEB) in the ATM team
- Involved in the Aquila Tucana project, testing withdrawing, depositing, credit card flows, login processes with hand vein tracking, and billing transactions
- Participated in the analysis and testing of the monitoring screen and identification of the ATM terminal on back-office screens
- Created receipt templates for customers at compass and self-service applications
- Prepared analysis documents related to Bantaş OMS screens for improvements and new requests resulting from joint meetings with Asset Management, ATM ops, and Bantaş teams
- Participated in the new infrastructure project (Wincor) tests of the Optimus project
- Worked on testing many flows such as withdrawal cash advances, installment cash advance, sending withdrawing money from TEB, credit card functions, accounts, and one number update.

5. BankPozitif - bankpozitif.com.tr

(Dec 2015 - Apr 2016)

Business Analyst

- Worked part-time
- Prepared analysis documents with Barış Makal
- Created process diagrams using Microsoft Visio to clarify all banking processes
- Tested the mobile banking app
- Created process diagrams on Visio for the software testing team to facilitate testing.